

ADDRESS: 192 Spencer Street 4B, Brooklyn, NY 11201

EMAIL: eric.fino@gmail.com

PHONE: 203.435.1340

PORTFOLIO: http://finomenon.com

PROFILE

I am a talented and hard-working technologist driven by a desire to create unique, exciting things. Throughout my 8+ year career in technology, I've had the fortune of working on some amazing projects. From Coca-Cola video mash-up widgets to Nike and Converse product customization software, I've made things that both inspire creativity and increase business profits. As a developer, my strengths are front-end web standards, responsive and adaptive design and ActionScript, though I strive to be language-agnostic and able to pick up the best tool for any given project. As a team leader, my broad range of experiences in video production, visual design and user experience help me to facilitate communication within multidisciplinary teams, resulting in cohesive processes and ultimately high-quality work.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Team Leader: R/GA, New York, NY (08/2012 - Present)

Assisted on strategic planning and co-facilitated business development workshops. Managed client and tech partner relationships, and a development team for the redesign of the Converse e-commerce website. The resulting prototype from this scope of work has since been used throughout the company as a standard for responsive and adaptive design.

Senior Open Standards Developer: R/GA, New York, NY (08/2011 - 08/2012)

Lead developer on projects that range from the HTML5 video web app portion of an in-store retail installation, to e-commerce websites with innovative features such as a mobile shoe customizer and an inline PDP.

Flash Developer: R/GA, New York, NY (04/2010 - 08/2011)

Worked on all-Flash e-commerce websites for high-profile clients, adding enhancement features and making performance optimizations. Developed highly innovative projects such as the Nike Team Sports uniform builder. Have also spear-headed the use of functional prototypes for pitches.

Senior Flash Engineer: Mediatronica, Inc., New York, NY (10/2006 – 04/2010)

Built customizable, XML driven user interface systems that generated sharable, branded Flash widgets with features revolved around gaming, web cameras, video, audio, and multi-user functionality. One notable application of this system let users rhythmically trigger video clips with their keyboard. The first iteration of this remix/mash-up tool, branded for the band Innerpartysystem, was nominated for a Webby in 2009.

Freelance Flash Developer: New York, NY (05/2006 - 03/2009)

Developed educational games for sites which include ShelSilverstein.com and MouseCookieBooks.com. Commissioned to build software for a kiosk game that teaches kids about the stock market, which is now on permanent exhibit at the Children's Museum of Houston. Have developed various interactive maps, utilizing APIs such as Google Maps and Papervision3D.

Teacher's Assistant: Advanced Education System, New York, NY (02/2006 - 08/2006)
Assisted in lectures and one-on-one training for a pilot program aimed at inspiring High School teachers to learn technology and incorporate it into their standard curriculum.

Web Developer/Graphic Design/Print Production: *Vertrue, Inc, Stamford, CT (8/2003 - 7/2004)* Created original web logo designs, and also built animated ad banners in both HTML and ActionScript 1.

Page: 1/2

EDUCATION

MPS Interactive Telecommunications Program

New York University - Tisch School of the Arts 09/2004 - 05/2006

BFA Graphic Design

University of Massachusetts Lowell 09/1999 – 12/2003

SKILLS

Management Skills

Scrum master Client and partner relationships
Source management: SVN, Git and Mercurial On-boarding and documentation

Task management: Fogbugz and JIRA Agile methodologies

Developer Skills

HTML XML CSS JSON Sass ISML

Compass Demandware Script Javascript ActionScript 3

JQuery Server-side ActionScript

Angular.js Papervision3D

Other languages

PHP Arduino MySQL Processing

IDEs and Other Tools

Sublime Text Grunt
Eclipse Tortoise
Charles Web Proxy Flash

XAMPP Flash Builder

Other Skills

Photoshop Premier Illustrator Blender

Final Cut Pro Adobe Media Encoder

References available upon request.